Finding Aid for Barber G. Buell papers, 1760-1935
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Barber G. Buell papers 1760-1935, 1849-1899
Buell, Barber G., 1823-1900.
1 oversize folders
3.3 linear feet
85854 Aa 2
Farmer at Volinia Township, Cass County, Michigan. Journals, financial records, papers of other family members.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came from Flora G. Buell (donor no. 2134 ) in 1947; additional materials came from Mrs. Bruce Buell (donor no. 4097 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Barber G. Buell was a farmer who lived in Little Prairie Ronde, Volinia Township, Cass County, Michigan. He was born in Newport New Hampshire in 1823. He came to Michigan and prospered as a livestock and fruit farmer.
The collection is divided into three series: Journals, Farm records, and Other Family Members.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Michigan--Cass County.; Buell, Barber G., 1823-1900.; Cass County (Mich.); Education--Michigan--Cass County.; Farmers--Michigan--Cass County.; Agricultural laborers--Michigan.; Michigan State College of Agriculture and Applied Science.; New Hampshire.; Michigan State Grange.; Volinia (Mich.: Township); Women--Michigan--Cass County.; Young Men's Christian Associations.; Women in agriculture--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Buell, Jennie.; Buell, Lincoln E., 1864-; Buell family.; Dwellings--Michigan--Volinia (Township); Volinia (Mich.: Township)--Dwellings.
Contributors:
Buell, J. Joseph.; Buell, Jennie.; Buell, Lincoln E., 1864-
Genre Terms:
Cyanotypes.; Diaries.; Photographs.
- Journals
  The journals date from 1869 to 1898 and provide a detailed daily account of life on the farm, weather conditions, comments on farm laborers, agricultural methods, and the economics of farming.
  - May 26, 1869-June 6, 1870 (Box 1)
  - June 8, 1870-January 16, 1871 (Box 1)
  - January 17, 1871-June 22, 1871 (Box 1)
  - June 23, 1871-January 17, 1872 (Box 1)
  - January 18, 1872-October 16, 1872 (Box 1)
  - October 17, 1872-May 10, 1873 (Box 1)
  - May 11, 1873-January 12, 1874 (Box 1)
  - January 13, 1874-July 25, 1874 (Box 1)
  - March 26, 1875-July 8, 1875 (Box 1)
  - July 26, 1874-January 30, 1875 (Box 1)
  - July 9, 1875-January 12, 1876 (Box 1)
  - January 13, 1876-December 12, 1876 (Box 1)
  - December 13, 1876-September 4, 1877 (Box 1)
  - September 5, 1877-May 14, 1878 (Box 1)
  - May 15, 1878-November 24, 1878 (Box 1)
  - November 25, 1878-June 13, 1879 (Box 1)
  - June 14, 1879-December 24, 1879 (Box 1)
  - December 25, 1879-August 4, 1880 (Box 1)
  - August 5, 1880-June, 1881 (Box 1)
  - June 10, 1881-January 25, 1882 (Box 1)
  - January 26, 1882-July 12, 1882 (Box 1)
  - July 13, 1882-January 3, 1883 (Box 1)
  - January 4, 1883-August 17, 1883 (Box 1)
  - August 18, 1883-April 24, 1884 (Box 1)
  - April 25, 1884-November 13, 1884 (Box 1)
  - November 14, 1884-April 27, 1885 (Box 1)
  - April 28, 1885-September 27, 1885 (Box 1)
  - September 28, 1885-February 16, 1886 (Box 2)
  - February 19, 1886-July 31, 1886 (Box 2)
  - August 1, 1886-December 1, 1886 (Box 2)
  - December 2, 1886-July 13, 1887 (Box 2)
  - July 14, 1887-March 22, 1888 (Box 2)
  - March 23, 1888-November 7, 1888 (Box 2)
  - November 8, 1888-October 17, 1889 (Box 2)
  - October 18, 1889-July 30, 1890 (Box 2)
  - July 31, 1890-April 30, 1891 (Box 2)
  - May 1, 1891-December 14, 1891 (Box 2)
  - December 15, 1891-December 26, 1892 (Box 2)
  - December 27, 1892-June 25, 1893 (Box 2)
  - June 26, 1893-April 16, 1894 (Box 2)
  - April 7, 1894-December 31, 1894 (Box 2)
  - January 1, 1895-December 31, 1895 (Box 2)
  - January 1, 1896-December 31, 1896 (Box 2)
  - January 1, 1897-June 4, 1898 (Box 2)
- Farm records
  Within the Farm Records series, there are account books, cash books, notebooks, scale books, and a stock horse record book. There are also a few speeches that he gave to various agricultural societies concerning hired labor, the social isolation of the farmer, agrarian protest and other farm related topics.
  - Farm journal and stock horse record book 1857-1869, 1 volumes (Box 2)
  - Farm journals 1897-1899, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - Scale books 1860s-1870s, 1 items; 4 volumes (Box 2)
  - Account books, daybooks, and other financial ledgers 1860s-1890s, 8 volumes (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous notebooks, diary fragments; notes from area Agricultural Fair (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous material: receipts and miscellaneous business and legal papers (Box 3)
  - Speeches, address, miscellaneous certificates, etc. 1852-1889 (Box 3)
- Other family members
  The Other Family Members series includes papers, 1891-1934, of Jennie Buell, secretary of the Michigan State Grange, concerning agriculture, ethics, Michigan State College and the education of farm women; papers, 1763-1813, of J. Joseph Buell, New Hampshire farmer; and papers, 1920-1921, of Lincoln E. Buell, state secretary of the Y.M.C.A.
  - Jennie Buell papers
    - Papers 1890-1935 [clippings and articles by Jennie Buell and correspondence] (Box 4)
    - White Ribbon Birthday book (Box 4)
    - Commonplace book (containing a collection of quotations from women writers with space for thoughts by the recipient (Box 4)
    - Notebook of clippings and quotations (Box 4)
  - Lincoln E. Buell papers
    - Papers 1920-1921 (Box 4)
  - J. Joseph Buell and Noyes family papers
    - Papers 1760-1813 (Box 4)
  - Photograph of Buell family members (Box 4)
    (see also oversize folder)